This is the police .
Help ! Help , please !
MADRID JUNE 15TH , 1991
01 : 35 A.M.
It 's okay .
Please , calm down so I can understand you .
- What happened ? - Please , you have to come !
He 's inside ! He 's inside !
Please , calm down . Tell me what you 're seeing .
Is there someone in your house ?
Hello !
Detective !
That 's the building there , 3C .
He 's here .
Mom ! Mom !
Detective !
We 're going to send someone right away . I need your address .
8 Gerardo Núñez Street .
Are you still there ?
Hello ?
Calling all units , we have a 402 at 8 Gerardo Núñez Street .
Any available cars please respond .
I repeat , 8 Gerardo Núñez Street .
EARLY MORNING , JUNE 15TH , 1991 ,
MADRID POLICE STATION 02-12 RECEIVED AN EMERGENCY PHONE CALL .
THIS STORY IS BASED ON THE POLICE REPORT
FILED BY THE DETECTIVE IN CHARGE OF THE CASE .
It 's confirmed .
There are four kids , two more are upstairs .
THREE DAYS EARLIER
THURSDAY , JUNE 12TH , 1991
Irene , you get the bathroom first .
Lucia , let 's go !
Get up .
Don 't make any noise .
Come on , buddy , get up .
Let 's go to school .
I want to go to school .
You want to go to school ?
Great .
- You wet the bed again ? ! - Yeah .
Come here .
Tell Irene to clean you up in the bathroom .
Vero !
- What 's wrong ? - Irene won 't let me in .
- I 'm taking a shower ! - Stop yelling !
He peed himself again . Clean him up , you 're older than him .
Fine .
I heard you . I 'm older , I came out first .
- Did you heat the milk ? - No .
Quite the older sister you are .
Lucia ! Pay attention , please !
The teacher said to bring pictures to look at the eclipse .
- Pictures ? - Yeah .
Your turn . Not pictures . Negatives , to shield our eyes .
Gross ! The towel smells like chicken .
You smell like wet chicken .
- Stop it ! Vero ! - Lucia , leave Irene alone .
Take one of the towels hanging outside .
Your shoes are untied .
You could have told me about the pictures last night .
- Me , me , me . - Fine , you do it .
- Everything OK ? - Yeah .
We had a birthday party and closed at 2 AM last night .
I 'm exhausted .
I came to get a picture for a class project .
You rest .
I 'm going to sleep some more .
I 'll see you later .
I heard it was night .
It 's all magic .
And a spirit invited you to dream .
I know that lately ,
I 've barely stopped .
I feel like I 'm rambling ...
Dawn breaks so early ,
and I 'm so alone ,
and I 'm not sorry for yesterday .
If the stars light you ,
today they 're your guide .
You feel so strong , you think ,
no one can touch you ...
- What 's up ? - I won 't wet the bed tomorrow .
- What ? - I won 't wet the bed tomorrow !
Good ! OK , go inside .
- How are you ? - Fine .
- You have fun ? - Yeah .
You know the earth always revolves around its own axis .
It also revolves around the sun .
But the moon , which is a satellite ,
revolves around the earth .
When the moon goes between the sun and the earth ,
an astronomical phenomenon occurs , and we call this a solar eclipse .
The moon 's shadow is cast on the earth 's surface .
It 's interesting , because it 's subjective .
It depends on the subject looking at it .
What we see here today in Madrid
is not what they see in Barcelona , or in Paris .
Next slide , please .
We can clearly see two different areas :
the shadow , or umbra area ,
and the penumbra area .
The umbra has no light ,
in total darkness .
Do YOU HAVE IT ?
The penumbra is the fragile shadow area .
Superstition has given many explanations for eclipses .
Next slide , please .
Primitive cultures believed
that the sky reflected what happened on earth .
So they believed that during eclipses
darkness reigned over light .
In many cultures , they thought that eclipses
were a good time for sacrifices .
Next slide , please .
Even human sacrifices .
In fact , they 'll explain it better in History class , but
the Maya believed that human blood was ...
Well , we 're out of time .
We have to go see the eclipse ,
but when we come back , we 'll talk about the different kinds .
Sara , help me with the window , please .
If you don 't have a picture , take it from the box over there , OK ?
OK .
And remember not to look at the sun , only look through the negative .
- Wait a minute . - No , let 's go .
- Just a second . - Girls , upstairs !
- Rosa , turn the projector off . - OK .
Wait ...
What 's wrong ?
We have to wait for Diana .
The one who got held back ?
Yeah , I told her what we were doing
and she wants to come .
Rosa , it was supposed to be between the two of us .
Well , now it 's between us , and Diana .
She 's really nice , anyway .
Besides ...
Remember Manolo ? With the spiked hair ?
The one who died in a motorcycle wreck !
- He was her boyfriend . - Why 'd you have to tell her ?
Sorry , it just slipped out .
But everybody knows it works better with odd numbers .
Everyone 's upstairs . The coast is clear now .
Begoña , what is this junk ?
Not with these !
Girls !
Get in place , it 's about to start .
Come on , over here .
Look , the negatives and the ...
Gross !
Stay together .
It 's this way !
Hey , wait for me !
Here .
This is disgusting . Have you guys done this before ?
Yeah , in my village . You said you have too , right ?
Yeah , but with paper cut-outs , you know ?
Never with an official board .
THE GREAT ENCYCLOPEDIA OF THE OCCULT
They 're dead , but that doesn 't mean they know everything , right ?
What did you bring ?
A picture .
What is that ?
You need a personal item of the person you want to contact .
A picture isn 't a personal item !
Of course it is !
It 's personal if it belongs to the person in the picture .
I didn 't bring any of Manolo 's stuff .
Can you see it ? The moon is going between .
See the ring ? See it ? Look , it 's the solar ring .
I can 't believe it !
Always look through ... Look at it with this , OK ?
It 's so beautiful !
It says to put your index finger on the glass .
- Close your eyes . - Why ?
Because you make contact faster .
Is anyone with us ?
Is there anyone here with us ?
It wasn 't me , I swear !
Who are you ?
You want to talk to one of us ?
Are you ... ?
Are you Veronica 's Dad ?
Do you want to talk to Veronica ?
S ...
P ...
Y ...
I spy .
- What do you spy ? - With my little eye ...
- What are you , a dumbass ? - You 're the dumbass !
I know you 're moving it .
Vero , did you move it ?
Who are you ?
It burns !
Vero , are you OK ? What 's happening ?
Vero !
No !
Please , Vero , let 's go !
Please , Vero !
Find the flashlight !
Diana , the flashlight !
- Where is it ? - Over there !
- Rosa , I can 't see ! - Fuck !
Here it is !
I 've got it , I 've got it here .
I 've got it .
Fuck !
The board is broken .
Where 's Veronica ?
Veronica ?
Veronica !
- Diana , go get help now ! - We 're gonna get in trouble .
Just go ! Shut up !
Veronica .
Veronica !
What 's wrong ?
What are you saying ?
Veronica .
Can you hear me ?
What happened to me ?
You fainted .
Follow my finger .
We tried to call your Mom , but we couldn 't get ahold of her .
She 's working .
Have you ever fainted like this before ?
No .
Did you eat breakfast ?
Yes .
Are you diabetic ?
Veronica !
Would you listen to me ?
Are you diabetic ?
I don 't know .
Blood sugar , any problems ?
Family history with diabetes ?
I don 't think so .
Did you take any drugs ?
- Pot , pills ... ? - No , no .
- You sure ? - I 'm sure .
Are you on your period ?
- Veronica , how old are you ? - Fifteen .
And you haven 't had your period ?
It 's probably low blood pressure .
You might have an iron deficiency .
If you can , I recommend eating red meat today .
Rest here for a few minutes .
Class is almost over .
- That 's so cool ! - Girls !
We always have to wait for you !
What happened to your hand ?
I cut it on some glass during recess .
Will you let me see ?
- Where 's Rosa ? - They left already .
- They didn 't wait for me ? - You missed the eclipse .
- The sun was totally dark . - The sun was black .
It was really cool .
Why weren 't you there ?
I was in the nurse 's office . Hey , don 't tell Mom about this .
- About what ? - About my cut , OK ?
- Zip your lips ... - Zip your lips
zip your lips
and throw away the key .
Come on , let 's go .
- What 's wrong , Irene ? - Sister Death is looking at you .
But she 's blind , she can 't see anything .
She 's blind .
- Wasn 't she deaf ? - No , blind , not deaf .
BEST MOM IN THE WORLD
- Hi , Mom ! - Hey there !
Can I have money to play Martians ?
Fine , you take it .
But just one round , then you go home , OK ?
Mom ?
- Not in front of the kids , man ! - Mom !
Give me the desserts for the 7 !
Stop for a second , please .
Why do you cover up such a beautiful face ?
Mom !
I 'll give you Tupperware with macaroni for tonight .
Get Antoñito and go home to eat .
Come on !
I 'm starving , my stomach is rumbling .
- They 're farts . - You 're the one farting .
Farts , farts , farts ...
- Irene , heat up the food . - Why me ?
- I always have to do it ! - Antoñito , go wash your hands .
Because I 'm the favorite .
What 's that ?
Nothing . Go set the table .
Vero !
Didn 't I tell you to set the table ?
You keep an eye on it .
- This much ? - Yeah .
Then , in front of the sun , there was ...
- It was all black and dark . - It was the moon !
You didn 't understand what the science teacher said .
Imagine a black ball and then a yellow ball .
The black one covers the yellow one , which is the sun .
- Irene , can you get some milk ? - You get it !
Rock , paper or scissors ?
Rock , paper , scissors .
One , two , three . Now !
- I won ! - No , best two out of three .
Rock , paper , scissors . One , two , three . Now !
Crap !
I beat you , I beat you , I beat you ...
- You cheated . - I cheated ? You cheated !
I never complain when you win .
There 's no milk left in the fridge , over .
It 's in the pantry , over .
Veronica ?
Hello ?
Irene , come here . Veronica 's all frozen up .
Veronica ?
- Veronica ! - Good thing it says easy-open .
Veronica !
What happened ?
You weren 't moving .
And you puked .
Are you OK ?
I 'm fine . Clean this up , please .
I 'll get it .
Yeah , OK .
Yeah , I 'll tell her .
Bye-bye .
Who was it ?
Rosa .
Why didn 't you give me the phone ?
She said she couldn 't come ,
she has to run some errands with her mom .
She didn 't ask to talk to me ?
No .
Hello ?
Hi , it 's Veronica . Is Rosa there ?
Hi , Vero . No , she isn 't here .
But she just called .
She just went out the door with Diana ...
I thought all three of you were meeting .
Vero .
Yeah , yeah . I 'm running late .
Tell her not to forget that she has to be home by eight .
OK , I 'll let her know .
Thanks , sweetheart . See you soon .
Centella gives me time to enjoy ,
Centella , Centella .
Centella gives me time to enjoy ...
Girls , put your PJs on .
Seven ! You 're in the bathroom !
Doesn 't count ! Vero told .
Let 's start over .
Centella gives me time to enjoy ...
Antoñito , that 's enough ! You sound like a parrot !
If you don 't know the jingle , why are you singing it ?
Yeah , yeah .
I see you ...
Oh , time to myself ...
Oh , time for life ...
Centella gives me time to enjoy ...
Centella ...
Girls , behave .
Scrub hard , I 'll be right back .
Girls , please .
What ?
Oh , time to myself , time for life ...
Centella gives me time to enjoy ...
Vero .
Vero !
Antoñito !
- Vero ! - Antoñito !
Vero !
Antoñito !
Antoñito , what 's wrong ?
It burns !
What happened ?
- What is that ? - It burns .
Did you touch the faucet ?
I didn 't do anything .
One , two , three , guess !
- A bird . - No .
A flower .
No .
A dog . Turn over .
One , two , three , guess !
- A balloon ! - Yes !
I 'm sorry I put the water on so hot .
It wasn 't you .
What ?
What did you say ?
I won 't wet the bed tomorrow .
Centella gives me time to enjoy ,
Centella , Centella .
Centella gives me a shiny floor ,
Oh , time to myself ,
Time for life .
Centella gives me time to enjoy ,
Centella , Centella .
Let 's go
leave this room , go to outer space
your eyes glaze over
all the same color .
Let 's go , leave this room
go to outer space , your eyes glaze over
all the same color .
While nothing matters !
Nine ...
Eight ...
Seven ...
Six ...
Five ...
Four ...
Three ...
Two ...
One !
Vero ...
What are you doing here ?
Veronica ...
Dad ?
FRIDAY , JUNE 13TH , 1991
08 : 29 A.M.
Antoñito , what 's wrong ?
It just leaked out .
It 's 8 : 30 ?
- Come on , run ! - Why 's it always Veronica 's fault ?
- No , no , don 't close ! - Please , just a second !
- By the skin of your teeth . - Thank you .
Thank you !
Becquer 's " Legends " started
with an introduction to transport the reader back in time .
A character would warn the protagonist about a prohibition ,
and then , this main character would cross the allowed limit
and suffer punishment for their infraction .
Alonso and Beatriz die because of Beatriz 's imprudence
when she forced Alonso to go up of the Mount of Spirits
on All Saints Day .
In " The Kiss , " Lope de Ayala attacks
his captain for profaning the statue of Doña Elvira .
In short , no one escapes the consequences
of passing the limit that divides reality from fantasy .
Please open your copy of " Legends , "
we 're going to read " The Mount of Spirits " together .
So I 'll start .
" On the night of the dead , the pealing of the bells
woke me at who knows what hour ;
the monotonous and eternal tolling
brought to mind this tradition ... "
- Yes ? - May I go to the bathroom ?
Of course .
" Once prodded , the imagination is a horse run wild ... "
You know when you go inside a house , and they 've just made French toast ?
It 's easy to tell the smell .
That smell of cinnamon ...
Fried bread ...
Warm milk .
If you close your eyes ,
it 's like they 're on a dish in front of you .
You could almost take a bite .
I was a Language and Lit teacher .
The French toast is a metaphor .
- What grade are you in ? - Ninth .
So you know what a metaphor is , right ?
And you also know we aren 't talking about desserts .
- Do you smoke ? - No .
Good .
They call you Sister Death .
I know .
- That doesn 't bother you ? - No .
I like it . Better than Sister Narcisa , right ?
What 's in your hand ?
How do you know I 'm holding something ?
You don 't always need eyes to see .
Can I see ?
What you did here is really dangerous .
I just wanted to talk to my Dad .
It 's not who you want to talk to .
It 's who you talk to .
If it isn 't my Dad , then who is it ?
- You have siblings , don 't you ? - Three of them .
You 'll have to protect them .
Protect them from what ?
You all stop moving !
Stop moving !
Don 't move !
But I 'm alone .
No .
You aren 't alone .
Someone answered your call .
And now walks with you .
Don 't move .
In the name of our Lord Jesus Christ ,
leave this body that does not belong to you .
Recess is over , girl .
Run , run , run .
Maybe you 'll get away .
Rosa !
Hi !
Who 's that ?
Felipe , my cousin 's classmate from trade school .
- What did you want ? - You 're mad at me .
Vero , why would I be mad at you ?
You didn 't come over yesterday .
I had to go with my Mom , didn 't your sister tell you ?
It 's because of yesterday , isn 't it ?
The ouija board is stupid . You say dumb stuff and move a glass .
You noticed something , too .
Rosa !
- You saw it , too , didn 't you ? - Saw what , Vero ?
- Since yesterday , I 've been seeing ... - Rosa !
We have to go quick , the store is going to close .
- Are you coming ? - Where ?
We 're throwing a party because Rosa 's parents are gone this weekend .
Why didn 't you tell me ?
Dude , she 's telling you now .
Besides , I doubt you can come , right ?
You have to babysit your brother and sisters .
Let 's go .
Vero !
- Drop by if you can . - Come on , we 're late !
Lucia , stop copying my homework !
THE GREAT ENCYCLOPEDIA OF THE OCCULT
This is boring ! It 's always the same !
Antoñito , that 's enough !
Go play in your room .
Lucia , stop copying your sister 's homework , you won 't learn !
- I learn when I copy , too . - You 're such a piece of work .
You 're going to do it , anyway . Why do you care ? You 're so selfish !
You 're always the same !
Then you do it one day and I 'll copy !
We could do rock , paper , scissors but you do it better .
It 's not that I do it better ...
You have siblings , don 't you ?
You 'll have to protect them .
VIKING SYMBOLS OF PROTECTION
Representing Madrid , Lucia Gomez , 19 years old
she is a doctor , lawyer , lifeguard and firefighter .
But there 's a secret nobody knows about Miss Madrid :
she 's a robot !
And the robot has super duper smart artificial intelligence .
Miss Madrid , soon to be contender for Miss Spain .
What 's that ?
A thing we made in class .
How ugly !
Take that , Miss Madrid !
Will you win the crown as Miss Spain ?
Yes or no !
Soon in theaters near you .
Miss Madrid is 25 years old , has 7 children ...
Who is it ?
Josefa .
- Where 's your Mom ? - At the bar .
Uh-huh . Wanna tell me what you all are up to ?
What 's wrong ?
The lamps ! Are you dancing or what ?
The lamps won 't stop shaking !
- We 're not doing anything . - Really ?
It looks like my ceiling is going to crash on me .
Something else :
I 've got a huge black stain , right on top of your bedroom .
You have moisture problems ?
- I don 't know , I 'll tell my Mom later . - Yeah , right !
If you see her , that is , huh ?
You 'll sleep well tonight with all that running around .
Fucking kids .
Shit !
Veronica .
What are you doing awake ?
Lucia , it isn 't funny . I can see your room from here .
Help us . You 're the one who called .
Don 't let it hurt us .
Irene !
Lucia !
Girls , wake up !
Vero ! Vero !
What are you doing ?
There was someone here who wanted to hurt you .
There 's no one in here !
We can 't see it , but it 's here .
Look !
The amulets got burned .
Take your mattresses , let 's go .
We 're sleeping together in the living room .
I 'm getting Antoñito .
It 's Benahavis .
Vero .
Go to sleep .
Why were you choking me ?
I wasn 't choking you .
I was protecting you .
From who ?
From something bad that came inside the house .
Who came inside the house ? Josefa ?
No .
A being from the other side .
An evil being .
A ghost ?
A spirit ?
Don 't be scared . I 'll protect you guys .
Because you 're the oldest ?
I 'm glad you 're my big sister .
I 'm glad you 're my little sister .
I 'm not little . I 'm in the middle ,
because Irene came out after .
That 's right .
Go to sleep . I 'll keep watch .
- Sorry , what 's going on ? - It 's a festival in Benahavis !
Veronica ...
Vero , what 's wrong ?
What 's going on ?
It 's back .
What 's this ?
- Mommy ! - Mommy !
Can you tell me what 's going on here ?
- A bad man wanted to kill Lucia . - Lucia , are you OK ?
Someone came in the house ?
No , they didn 't come inside . They were already here .
- Vero ! - Nothing happened , Mom .
But was someone in the house or not ?
- No . - Yes .
- I 'm calling the police . - A spirit .
- What ? - Yeah , a ghost .
I didn 't see it , but Vero did .
- Were you watching scary movies again ? - Kind of .
Don 't worry , Mom . Vero protects us from the spirit .
Come on , let 's pick all this up and go to bed .
And you go to your room !
- But , Mom ... - No buts ! Go to your room .
What happened ?
- Tell me ! - Nothing .
Your sisters are little and they 've got a huge imagination .
Don 't give them weird ideas because then they can 't sleep .
How do you know if they can or can 't sleep ?
You 're never home ! You don 't know what goes on here .
So what goes on here ?
- He wants to hurt us ! - Who ? !
I don 't know ! I 'm the one who called him with the ouija board .
You played the ouija board with your sisters ?
- No , with Rosa ! - But ...
Why are you playing with such dark things ?
I wanted to talk to Dad .
I know you don 't care .
You stuffed his pictures in a box so you don 't have to look at him .
Don 't say that !
- I just wanted to talk to him ! - That 's enough !
You 're reading too much of that stuff , and it 's having an effect on you .
It 's the truth .
Vero ...
I need you to grow up .
I need to be able to count on you .
Because I 'm on my own .
I 'm the one on my own .
You 're not making it easy . I 'm really tired .
We 'll talk more tomorrow .
Nine , eight , seven ,
six , five , four ,
three , two , one !
- Vero ! - Vero , get up !
- Wake up ! - Come on !
- Come on ! - Get up !
Let 's go !
Leave me alone , let me sleep !
- We 're hungry ! - Come on !
We 've got lots to do !
We 're hungry !
- What are you doing ? - We 're hungry !
Get out , leave me alone !
- Come on ! - Get up !
Let 's play a game . Give me your arm .
What are you talking about ?
What are you doing ?
Stop it !
Stop !
Don 't !
Mom ! Mom ! Help me , Mom !
Mom , help me !
Mom , Mom !
Mom , Mom ...
Mom !
Leave me alone ! Mom !
Mom , help me !
Mom ...
Help me , Mom .
- I can 't hear you . - Mom !
I need you to grow up .
Mom ...
Mom !
Mom ... !
SATURDAY , JUNE 14TH , 1991
10 : 40 A.M.
- Did you make breakfast ? - Wait for the show to finish .
Always the same , I 'm sick of you guys !
Wait .
Why 's this book here ? You don 't know how to read !
Dad came to read it to me .
Come again ?
- Dad came ? - He 's coming back again tonight .
What else did he say ?
That he 's going to take me to where he lives .
Antoñito , listen to me .
Listen .
If he comes back , don 't listen to him , OK ?
Plug your ears .
How do you plug your ears ?
Great , like that .
And you call me , OK ?
Yell my name really loud .
OK ?
Kids , let 's go !
- Hi , Mom ! - Hey there !
- What are you doing here ? - I need to go to Rosa 's house .
- Right now ? - For homework . Can they stay here ?
- Yeah . But come back soon ! - OK !
They 're right . You 're a crazy old woman .
- Then why are you back ? - You can see the shadows , like me !
Maybe we 're both crazy .
I 've been trying to stop seeing them for a long time .
I did this to myself , you know ?
Back then I didn 't know you don 't need eyes to see .
I don 't know how to protect myself from them .
Amulets and crosses don 't work , they don 't scare them !
Crosses ? God has got nothing to do with it .
Leave Him out of it .
How can I make them go away ?
The same way they came in .
They have to go back through the door you opened .
Bid them farewell .
Then you 'll have to destroy it .
- Destroy the ouija board ? - No , the door !
You have to do right what you did wrong .
What 's wrong ?
Sister , again ?
I don 't know how you can get all the way down here .
What are you doing here on a Saturday ?
Sister was helping me with a project .
She 's in no condition to help anyone .
This way , Sister .
The answer is in the books .
Look what great advice she gives .
You have to do right what you did wrong .
Careful , Sister .
" You have to do right what you did wrong . "
" You should never end a séance without ... "
Without what ?
" You have to do right what you did wrong . "
" You have to do right ... "
" You should never end a séance without saying goodbye .
Whatever you don 't say goodbye to , stays with you .
If it doesn 't work , try again another time . "
" Whatever you don 't say goodbye to , stays with you . "
You have to do right what you did wrong .
" You have to do right what you did wrong . "
The answer is in the books .
" Whatever you don 't say goodbye to , stays with you . "
You have to do right what you did wrong .
" You have to do right what you did wrong . "
" You should never end a séance without saying goodbye . "
Hi .
You made it .
Rosa , I know what we have to do .
- Why 'd you bring that ? - We have to do it again !
- What ? - We didn 't say goodbye !
Whatever you don 't say goodbye to , stays with you .
- What ? - It says so right here .
- Cut the bullshit . - We have to do it again !
- Put it away ! - Let 's go to your room .
Where 's Diana ?
- Calm down ! - Where 's Diana ?
- Put it away ! - Diana !
- Let 's go to your room . Diana ! - Veronica !
Diana !
Where 's Diana , have you seen her ?
- Veronica ! - Diana !
Have you seen Diana ?
What are you talking about ?
Diana ! Have you seen Diana ?
- No . - Who is Diana ?
Diana !
- Diana ! - No , what 's your problem ?
- You haven 't seen her ? - Veronica , please .
Diana !
Diana .
Diana , come here .
- What the fuck are you doing ? - Come on , we have to do it .
- Do what ? - The three of us together .
- Let me go , you 're crazy ! - Come on , Diana !
- Leave me alone ! - Let go of me !
- Kicking you the hell out ! - Come on , Diana , Rosa !
Rosa ! Rosa !
Rosa , we have to do it again .
- You don 't remember , do you ? - Remember what ?
You whispered something to me the other day .
What did I say ?
Tell me , Rosa !
You said you were going to die today .
- What ? - Vero , I 'm sorry .
- What did you say ? - We were scared , we didn 't ...
What 's that ?
Did you bite yourself ?
No , Rosa . I didn 't .
Come on , let 's go .
Rosa !
Mom !
Hey , you 're in the way !
Can we go home now ?
Wait .
Mom !
Where were you all day ?
Take the kids , they can 't stay here forever !
Give me the leftovers for the kids . Coming !
This is always dirty .
Because you always get it dirty .
Mom !
What ?
Mom , close the bar .
Right now , let 's all go somewhere .
What are you talking about ?
Mom , it doesn 't come when you 're home .
Here we go again ...
I 'd love to close and eat with you , but I can 't .
- Ana ! - Coming .
Look ...
Want to go to the park tomorrow ?
To spend the day , like before .
What do you think ? I 'll make sandwiches to eat there .
You want to ?
Ana , the leftovers !
You grab them .
Kids , let 's go .
Finally !
- Let 's go . - Are we going home ?
Let 's go , sweetheart .
Veronica !
Goal !
Pedro Riesco scored . After Ribera 's mistake ,
the first goal in the game for the team ...
You have to do right what you did wrong .
- We 're going to play a game . - What game ?
We 're going to play a game where you have to do what I say .
This game sucks .
Grab the candles in the top drawer .
Antoñito , draw this on the hallway walls .
- OK ! - Great .
I get to draw on the wall .
Mom 's going to ground you until you 're at least 40 .
Move the furniture . We need to have space .
SATURDAY , JUNE 14TH , 1991 23 : 45
VIKING SYMBOLS OF PROTECTION
SYMBOLS OF INVOCATION
Not you . Just the three of us .
Sit over there .
You guys close your eyes .
Is anyone here with us ?
Is there anyone here with us ?
Who 's here with us ?
Are you here ?
Yes .
We 're here to say goodbye to you .
You need to leave this place .
No .
We command you ! Repeat after me , girls .
We command you !
This isn 't your house !
Leave !
" To properly conclude the séance and bid farewell ,
participants should sing a mantra or a soft song . "
- We didn 't do that , either . - What 's a mantra ?
I don 't know .
But it says a soft song works , too .
Which one ?
One all three of us know .
Centella .
Centella gives me time to enjoy ...
Centella , Centella .
What is that ?
Time to myself , time for life ,
Centella gives me time to enjoy ...
Centella , Centella .
Girls , keep going . We can 't stop .
Time for life ...
Centella gives me time to enjoy ...
Centella , Centella .
Time to myself , time for life ,
Centella gives me time to enjoy ...
Centella , Centella , time to myself ...
Come on , don 't stop !
Centella gives me time to enjoy ...
Centella , Centella .
Gross , it stinks .
... time to enjoy , Centella , Centella .
Lucia , don 't stop .
Centella gives me time to enjoy ... Centella , Centella .
Keep singing !
Don 't stop singing !
Wait here .
Don 't leave .
He 's here !
- This is the police . - Help ! Help , please !
Please , calm down so I can understand you .
- What happened ? - Please , help us ! He 's inside !
He 's inside !
There 's someone in the house ?
Calm down . We 're going to send someone right away . I need your address .
8 Gerardo Núñez Street .
Antoñito , stay here ! What are you doing ?
Antoñito !
No !
He 's in the bathroom !
Antoñito !
Antoñito , Antoñito !
Girls , stay there ! He 's in the bathroom .
Antoñito !
Antoñito ?
Are you OK , buddy ?
Are you OK ?
Let 's go .
Girls ! Girls !
Girls , where are you ?
Irene , where 's your sister ?
Irene !
Lucia , let 's go !
Let 's
Run !
Come on , run ! Let 's go !
Paco , the cops !
What 's going on ?
Girls , run ! Faster , come on !
Hurry !
Let 's go !
Run , girls , run !
Open the door .
- Vero ! - Vero !
Where 's Antoñito ?
SUNDAY , JUNE 15TH , 1991 01 : 50 A.M.
Mom ! Mom ! Mom !
What happened ? What happened ?
Where 's Antoñito , where 's Vero ?
Where 's Vero ?
Antoñito !
Antoñito ?
Antoñito .
Vero . Vero . Vero .
- Vero , Vero ... - Antoñito , come on .
- Vero , Vero , Vero ... - Antoñito , let 's go .
- Vero , Vero , Vero ... - Antoñito , it 's me .
No , no , no , no .
If he comes back ,
don 't listen to him , OK ?
Plug your ears .
And you call me , OK ?
Yell my name really loud .
Vero , Vero , Vero ...
You have siblings , don 't you ?
You 'll have to protect them .
Don 't worry , Mom . Vero protects us from the spirit .
You 're reading too much of that stuff , and it 's having an effect on you .
Vero ! Vero !
What are you doing ?
We can 't see it , but it 's here .
Why were you choking me ?
I wasn 't choking you .
I was protecting you .
- Did you touch the faucet ? - I didn 't do anything .
Antoñito !
I 'm sorry I put the water on so hot .
Did you move it ?
Did you bite yourself ?
It wasn 't you .
Someone answered your call .
And now walks with you .
If it isn 't my Dad , then who is it ?
It 's me .
Vero , Vero ...
Buddy , come here . It 's OK .
Come with me . That 's it .
- Where 's Vero ? - Vero ? She 's fine .
Pellicer , send the medics up . I repeat , send the medics up .
Vero ! Vero !
Veronica .
Sweetie ...
Detective .
Go ahead .
The girl just died .
SUNDAY , JUNE 15TH , 1991 02 : 00 A.M.
JUNE 15TH , 1,991 , DETECTIVE JOSÉ RAMÓN ROMERO
WENT TO THE HOME ON CALLE GERARDO NUÑEZ NUMBER 8 ,
IN RESPONSE to AN EMERGENCY CALL .
IN THEIR STATEMENT , FAMILY MEMBERS DECLARED
THAT AFTER A SÉANCE WITH THE OUIJA BOARD ,
THE GIRL HAD SEVERAL STRANGE SYMPTOMS
AND PARANORMAL EVENTS TOOK PLACE AT THE HOME .
TWO OF THE INSPECTING AGENTS SUDDENLY HAD TO LEAVE THE BUILDING ,
DUE TO NAUSEA , DIZZINESS AND SHAKING . THEY REMAINED 2 WEEKS OFF THE FORCE .
ONE MONTH AFTER THE EVENTS , ROMERO REQUESTED A TRANSFER .
IN THE INSPECTOR 'S REPORT , ROMERO SPEAKS OF PHENOMENA
THAT IS " LITERALLY INEXPLICABLE , " THE FIRST POLICE REPORT IN SPAIN
WHERE AN OFFICER CERTIFIES HAVING WITNESSED PARANORMAL ACTIVITY .